<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dbhub.io on DB Browser for SQLite</title>
    <link>/tags/dbhub.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dbhub.io on DB Browser for SQLite</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/dbhub.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Go library for working with your DBHub.io databases</title>
      <link>/blog/new-go-library-for-working-with-your-dbhub-io-databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-go-library-for-working-with-your-dbhub-io-databases/</guid>
      <description>For anyone with an interest in Go programming, there&amp;rsquo;s now a library to access and query your databases on DBHub.io:
https://github.com/sqlitebrowser/go-dbhub
Documentation is in place, code quality is good, and there are worked examples for each function call.
It&amp;rsquo;s still in early stages of development, but seems to work well already. 😄
What works now  Run read-only queries (eg SELECT statements) on databases, returning the results as JSON List the names of tables, views, and indexes present in a database List the columns present in a table or view, along with their details (Added 2020-08-02) - Generate a diff between two databases or revisions, to transform one into the other (Added 2020-08-04) - List the branches of a database (Added 2020-08-04) - Download a complete database (Added 2020-08-05) - List the databases in your account  Still to do  Tests for each function Retrieve index details for a database Return the list of available databases Download a complete database Upload a complete database Retrieve database commit history details (size, branch, commit list, whatever else is useful) Investigate what would be needed for this to work through the Go SQL API Anything else that people suggest and seems like a good idea 😄  Requirements  Go version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New API for remotely executing SQLite queries</title>
      <link>/blog/new-api-for-remotely-executing-sqlite-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-api-for-remotely-executing-sqlite-queries/</guid>
      <description>For anyone wanting to run SQL queries against their uploaded databases, there&amp;rsquo;s now an API server: https://api.dbhub.io
As a starting point, there&amp;rsquo;s just one API call (/v1/query), and it only runs SELECT queries (eg read only database). That should be useful enough for many things though.
Query parameters Query parameters are passed via POST only, and all results are in a fairly verbose JSON format.
 apikey - Your API key.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding basic visualisation capability to dbhub.io</title>
      <link>/blog/adding-basic-visualisation-capability-to-dbhub-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adding-basic-visualisation-capability-to-dbhub-io/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve begun adding the first visualisation pieces to DBHub.io, so people can display charts from their data.
eg:
This is only the starting point (eg a simple vertical bar chart) while we experiment, to find a good workflow that&amp;rsquo;s easy for people to use + customise.
We&amp;rsquo;re aiming to add several more chart types to choose from, and there being a selection of easy-to-use predefined templates as well.
Advanced users will ideally be able to input their own SQL queries for generating the data points to visualise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New landing page for DBHub.io</title>
      <link>/blog/new-landing-page-for-dbhub-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-landing-page-for-dbhub-io/</guid>
      <description>Our sister website, DBHub.io - where people can backup their databases, share them with others, and collaboratively develop data - has a proper landing page from today:
 https://dbhub.io
It required quite a lot of effort to assemble, even though it&amp;rsquo;s just a simple description, screenshots (click them!), and an overview video. 😉
Please take a look, create an account (it&amp;rsquo;s free), and try things out.
The website code is fully Open Source, and is gaining interesting + useful capabilities over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard username/password logins now working for DBHub.io</title>
      <link>/blog/standard-username-password-logins-now-working-for-dbhub-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/standard-username-password-logins-now-working-for-dbhub-io/</guid>
      <description>A small, but important, update about DBHub.io logins. 😉
People can now create accounts using their own username/password again, instead of needing to login via GitHub, Google, or LinkedIn.
It used to work (ages ago), but Auth0 found a security problem with the version of NodeJS they were using, so disabled it for everyone last year. It was fixable by changing some stuff, which has now been done.
On a related note&amp;hellip; login (using username/password) only works if &amp;ldquo;3rd party cookies&amp;rdquo; aren&amp;rsquo;t blocked in your web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First (beta) DBHub.io server with DB4S integration is online</title>
      <link>/blog/first-beta-dbhub-io-server-with-db4s-integration-is-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first-beta-dbhub-io-server-with-db4s-integration-is-online/</guid>
      <description>The first &amp;ldquo;db4s-beta&amp;rdquo; server is now online, which DB4S 3.10.0-beta can store/retrieve databases in.
Feel free to [create an account](https://db4s-beta.dbhub.io/justinclift/DB4S%20download%20stats.sqlite) and try things out (the link in the top right of that page). 😄 Don&amp;rsquo;t store important data in it yet though, as we don&amp;rsquo;t have backups set up yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial DBHub.io server online</title>
      <link>/blog/initial-dbhub-io-server-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/initial-dbhub-io-server-online/</guid>
      <description>An initial DBHub.io server is online, running our latest development code. Testing and feedback is encouraged.
Note - The data on this server will probably be wiped/reset every few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New sister project: DBHub.io</title>
      <link>/blog/new-sister-project-dbhub-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/new-sister-project-dbhub-io/</guid>
      <description>Added first page for our new sister project: DBHub.io. Take a look! 😄</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>